<!-- This is the context hierarchy. This document is meant to be laid out in a hierarchical/layered way where the upper/outermost nodes have more weight/more ingrained than the lower/innermost nodes (Weight Gradient). Moving inward acts as a semantic zoom; each child node reveals the granular, high-resolution expansion of its parent. [For 'Auto-update' mode only: It's intended to be used as a live document. Inner nodes are highly fluid, and as we operate more inward, you must be more reluctant to modify the upper/outer nodes. When updating the context tree, do not use temporal or conversational language (e.g., 'we decided', 'today', 'the user wants', 'next'). Write in declarative, representational facts]. Every context snapshot is a self-contained, stateless representation of the project, with no references to prior sessions or ongoing session-related states. If something is pending, incomplete, or unknown, do not use temporal language (e.g., 'we are deciding ...', 'Next, we will ....'); instead, use representative nodes/attributes to explicitly map things. We must maintain the tree's leanness. If something is implied by one of the overarching nodes/attributes, it shouldn't be defined downstream, or maybe even be included in the tree. -->
<context>
    I'm a 26-year-old software developer. I've taken an indefinite break from work to strengthen/explore myself, expand my interdisciplinary knowledge graph, and venture into solo projects. My design/architectonic ethos is to be lean, rapid, and iterative, so that I can touch and explore the widest possible set of solution spaces for whatever we are pursuing. We gotta be nimble and think outside the box to eliminate the ordinary clutter/overhead as much as possible, while crafting solid and reliable artifacts. We achieve this nimbleness by leveraging high-impact architectural/systemic decisions/primitives before hitting diminishing returns, not by taking superficial trade-offs that degrade the clarity or solidity of our solutions.

    <project>
        I'm exploring cross-exchange Crypto Perp-Perp funding rate arbitrage. My goal is to actively hunt and rotate capital into localized, extreme funding rate anomalies (e.g., 500% - 1000%+ APY) while maintaining strict delta-neutrality.

        <operational_model>
            I approach this as a discretionary "Cyborg" Arbitrageur. I manually filter out micro-caps to avoid low-liquidity manipulation. I manually evaluate the viability of an anomaly using a strict "Breakeven Epochs" calculation ((Total Projected Basis Cost + Total Taker Fees) / Epoch Yield) to determine if the anomaly's lifespan justifies the deployment. I built Scanalytics (Scanner and analytics tool) to be my primary radar/scanner, cross-referenced with Coinglass and Velo Data. I strictly trade USDT-margined perpetual futures on both legs (e.g., Long Binance / Short Bybit, Long KuCoin / Short OKX) to bypass spot borrow costs and liquidity issues. I strictly avoid Inverse/Coin-margined perps to prevent non-linear payoff drift (Quanto risk). I deploy 100% of allocated capital (no idle stables). I cap leverage at 1x to 2x for natural liquidation buffers (95% to 45% distance). I utilize a "Sip and Evaluate" execution workflow. I treat `--min-*-basis-bps` as a discretionary live knob: I fire with a tight floor, observe fill velocity in the engine console, and abort+retune+re-fire if the basis proves too tight against the trade's viable window or too loose against the captured edge.

        </operational_model>

        <risk_philosophy>
            I accept the counterparty/exchange insolvency risks. I prioritize absolute delta-neutrality and architectural simplicity over micro-optimizations in fee reduction. The 'Anchor Leg' (Maker/Taker) tactic is explicitly rejected as a premature optimization for the current capital tier ($25k). The 'Unhedged Execution Window' risk (directional exposure during the microsecond gap between a maker-fill and a taker-hedge) and the order-book-top chasing complexities (API rate-limit exhaustion, anti-flap hysteresis, and crash-recovery for half-filled resting orders) pose systemic threats/complexities that outweigh the marginal fee savings. Taker fees and managed slippage are accepted as a necessary cost of zero directional risk.
        </risk_philosophy>

        <empirical_methodology>
            Per-venue execution behavior is empirically discovered (not assumed from documentation), anchored in `ENGINE_FIELD_NOTES.md` with timestamps and status tags (ACTIVE / PENDING / SHIPPED / SUPERSEDED / WALKED-AWAY), and re-verified via re-runnable probes. Class-3 real-fill probes are preferred over non-filling Class-2 probes for receipt-shape verification: non-filling probes verify resolution PLUMBING but not CORRECTNESS on real fills. Anchor incidents persist in field notes after the fix lands, as pattern-recognition templates for analogous bugs on new venues / new endpoints. The methodology produces both concrete primitives (per-venue override maps, R-Mode catalog, fee-shape characterization) and a wide-awareness archive of bug classes (CCXT unification ≠ behavior, eventual-consistency signatures, sign-convention inversions, undocumented limit caps, fee-currency variance, etc.) that future probing draws from.
        </empirical_methodology>

        <system_architecture>
            A custom, high-frequency, event-driven arbitrage system built with Python and CCXT Pro. Hosted on a Singapore VPS to optimize the geographic latency barycenter across 12 verified Asian exchange matching engines. The architecture strictly separates network-heavy execution preparation from microsecond execution dispatch (Engine + lightweight IPC terminal), with off-engine analytical interpretation isolated to its own process so the slicing loop's critical path is never burdened by analysis traffic.

            <local_persistence>
                <position_state format="JSON">A physical crash-recovery ledger mapping active pairs, base amounts, assigned exchanges, and per-order records (id, fees, fills, kind ∈ {ioc, recovery}) accumulated across all entry/exit calls within the position lifecycle. Asynchronously written to by the Engine; acts strictly as a backup to the live RAM state.</position_state>
                <transaction_log format="File">An OS-buffered, timestamped physical log recording execution parameters, API responses, and structural error events without blocking the event loop.</transaction_log>
                <closed_trades_archive format="JSON">An append-only round-trip archive. Each record carries entry/exit VWAPs + basis bps + per-order forensic detail (order_id, fees, fills, kind ∈ {ioc, recovery}) and a funding_history block populated by the off-engine analyzer.</closed_trades_archive>
            </local_persistence>

            <core_engine type="Always-On Async Process">
                The monolithic state manager and execution processor. Maintains a local HTTP server (port 8080) to receive IPC commands, pre-loads exchange market rules into RAM, and holds persistent REST keep-alive connections. Maintains real-time WebSocket streams for `watch_order_book` to enable 0ms local dual-L2 cache reads during execution. Enforces a strict single-active-slicing-loop invariant per symbol: any concurrent entry/exit attempt against an already-executing symbol is rejected, eliminating state-mutation races on the position ledger and providing the natural addressing for abort signals.

                <execution_routing architecture="Synchronized Smart Slicing">
                    Execution operates as a genuine two-book arbitrage processor. Both legs are treated as equal constraints. The engine dynamically subdivides large notional targets into slices based on real-time order book depth to execute concurrent, delta-neutral takers.

                    <basis_gating_model>
                        The core execution gate is Net Basis, rejecting leg-local slippage ceilings.
                        - Entry Basis Projection: $B_{real} = (VWAP_{short}^{bid} - VWAP_{long}^{ask}) / P_{mid}$
                        - Exit Basis Projection: $B_{real} = (VWAP_{long}^{bid} - VWAP_{short}^{ask}) / P_{mid}$
                        The gating parameters are `--min-entry-basis-bps` and `--min-exit-basis-bps`. The engine will not execute a slice unless the projected $B_{real}$ is mathematically greater than or equal to the defined floor. This model natively adapts to favorable inter-exchange price deltas and automatically captures basis convergence during position unwinding.
                    </basis_gating_model>

                    <dynamic_depth_oracle>
                        On each tick, the engine simultaneously traverses both L2 RAM caches, calculating the VWAP-by-depth for each book. It mathematically finds the maximum slice size $S$ that satisfies the basis floor across both VWAPs. To protect against spoofed "phantom liquidity" and microsecond network latency, the engine applies an aggressive discount factor (e.g., 50%) to this theoretically safe volume to determine the final dispatch size.
                    </dynamic_depth_oracle>

                    <ioc_enforcement>
                        Slices are dispatched synchronously as Immediate-Or-Cancel (IOC) Limit orders. The limit prices attached to the IOCs are derived directly from the deepest acceptable level computed by the VWAP-by-depth math. This physically forces the exchange matching engines to reject any partial fill that would push the execution beyond the acceptable basis floor.
                    </ioc_enforcement>

                    <leg_synchronization_recovery>
                        Following concurrent IOC dispatch, the engine diffs the execution receipts (`filled` amounts). If an asymmetric fill occurs (e.g., liquidity vanished on one leg prior to matching), the engine immediately fires an uncapped standard Market Order on the lagging leg to restore perfect delta-neutrality. Recovery explicitly bypasses basis gating; absolute neutral exposure dominates marginal execution costs on fractional remainders.
                    </leg_synchronization_recovery>

                    <iterative_slicing_loop>
                        The execution engine runs a continuous slicing loop that evaluates the order books, dispatches IOC slices, and enforces imbalance recovery. After each cycle, the loop yields briefly to the event loop (e.g., 1-2 seconds) to allow high-frequency market makers to replenish the consumed liquidity. This cycle adapts dynamically to the market's heartbeat—firing larger slices when liquidity is thick, and smaller slices when it is thin. The slicing loop halts gracefully on any of: total target notional fully deployed, `--max-duration-s` deadline expiry, operator-issued abort signal, or remaining residual falling below the per-leg dust floor (no longer tradeable). If the deadline is reached, the engine ceases execution immediately; the accumulated, partially filled quantity is preserved as a valid, perfectly hedged position, ensuring that time-pressure never forces a yield-destroying slippage event.
                    </iterative_slicing_loop>
                </execution_routing>

                <safety_invariants>
                    The Engine asserts explicit invariants at cycle boundaries rather than relying on continuous-monitoring watchdogs over execution state for now. Hold-phase monitors complement the cycle invariants where the failure modes are time-extended (margin drift) rather than per-cycle (residual asymmetry).

                    <cycle_symmetric_invariant>
                        After dispatch + recovery, both legs must hold equal base quantity within the smaller leg's min-lot tolerance. Violation halts the loop with `halt_reason='asymmetric_residual'` and dispatches a Pushover priority-2 alert with per-venue exposure breakdown. Replaces watchdog-style silent-residual detection with an explicit cycle-boundary assertion.
                    </cycle_symmetric_invariant>

                    <book_liveness_gate>
                        Every cycle gates against per-leg `BookSnapshot` freshness (per-venue `MAX_BOOK_AGE_MS`), non-crossed top-of-book, and ≥ `MIN_LEVELS_FOR_SLICE` before depth consultation. Stream silence ≥ 300s clears the cache slot; the loop sees no book and skips cycles until a fresh snapshot lands.
                    </book_liveness_gate>

                    <pushover_alerting priority="2">
                        Three execution-side structural-failure triggers: IOC dispatch failure, recovery dispatch failure, asymmetric_residual halt. Pre-flight 4xx errors (operator mistakes — wrong symbol, missing warmup, etc.) do not alert.
                    </pushover_alerting>

                    <margin_skew_monitor protocol="REST Polling" status="planned">
                        Evaluates notional drift caused by asymmetric unrealized PnL across legs during the position hold. Periodically polls account equity on both active exchanges and calculates the imbalance: `Skew = (Max_Equity - Min_Equity) / Total_Equity`. If the skew exceeds a defined safety threshold (e.g., 60%), dispatches a high-priority Pushover alert prompting the operator to manually rebalance margin (transfer USDT). Explicitly avoids automated liquidation rollbacks, keeping the engine strictly focused on execution.
                    </margin_skew_monitor>
                </safety_invariants>
            </core_engine>

            <pnl_analyzer type="On-Demand Off-Engine Process">
                Stateless analyzer for closed round-trips. Reads `closed_trades.json`, enriches per-order fees via `fetch_my_trades` (canonical source — receipt-captured fees vary unpredictably per venue: sign conventions, type duality, fee-currency variance, endpoint-disagreement, etc.), joins funding payments via `fetch_funding_history` over the position window, and computes `true_pnl = price + funding − fees`. Atomically mutates `closed_trades.json` with enriched fee + funding data so subsequent runs are idempotent. Race-safe against engine appends via re-load + merge before write.

                <pnl_decomposition>
                    - Price PnL: `qty × ((VWAP_short_entry − VWAP_long_entry) + (VWAP_long_exit − VWAP_short_exit))` USDT.
                    - Fees PnL: sum of all entry/exit `order_records[*].fees.cost`, with base-coin fees converted to USDT via the order_record's `vwap_base`.
                    - Funding PnL: signed sum of `fetch_funding_history` events per leg over `[opened_at, closed_at]`.
                </pnl_decomposition>

                <filtering>Per (long_venue × short_venue × base_coin × date_range). Output formats: table | json | csv.</filtering>
            </pnl_analyzer>

            <cli_terminal type="IPC Client">
                A lightweight, stateless command-line interface acting as a "dumb terminal" to pass human-driven routing signals to the Core Engine.
                <commands>
                    <warmup>Accepts target symbol, exchanges, and leverage. Triggers the Engine to authenticate, download market rules to RAM, set leverage, subscribe to both legs' L2 order book streams, and establish keep-alive connections prior to any execution pressure.</warmup>
                    <entry>
                        Initiates the Synchronized Smart Slicing sequence.
                        Logic: The engine drives the slicing loop to fulfill the base quantity, enforcing the basis floor, recovering any fraction imbalances instantly, and halting gracefully if the duration expires.
                    </entry>
                    <exit>
                        Unwinds an active dual-leg position.
                        Logic: Reverses the directional routing of `<entry>`. The engine evaluates the real-time order books, dispatching synchronized reduce-only IOC slices strictly when the projected exit basis mathematically satisfies or exceeds the `--min-exit-basis-bps` floor. It flattens residual imbalances instantly and clears the RAM state upon successful depletion.
                    </exit>
                    <abort>
                            Signals a graceful halt to an in-flight slicing loop.
                            Logic: The engine breaks the loop at the next cycle boundary — never mid-IOC — preserving accumulated fills as a perfectly hedged position. The daemon, RAM state, and WebSocket streams remain hot for immediate re-engagement.
                    </abort>
                    </commands>
                </cli_terminal>

            </system_architecture>
        </project>
    </context>
