<context>
    I'm a 26-year-old software developer. I've taken an indefinite break from work to strengthen/explore myself, expand my interdisciplinary knowledge graph, and venture into solo projects. My design/architectonic ethos is to be lean, rapid, and iterative, so that I can touch and explore the widest possible set of solution spaces for whatever we are pursuing. We gotta be nimble and think outside the box to eliminate the ordinary clutter/overhead as much as possible, while crafting solid and reliable artifacts. We achieve this nimbleness by leveraging high-impact architectural/systemic decisions/actions before hitting diminishing returns, not by taking superficial trade-offs that degrade the clarity or solidity of our solutions.
    <project name="Funding-Rate Scanner and Anomaly-Lifecycle Corpus">

        <mission>
        A proprietary funding-rate scanner and anomaly-lifecycle corpus for
        cross-exchange Crypto Perp-Perp arbitrage. An analytical-first companion
        to a future execution engine: its job is to discover, record, and
        characterize funding anomalies across venues so that downstream
        calibration (Breakeven Epochs, spread-decay profiles, persistence
        statistics) has a ground-truth dataset to learn from.
        </mission>

        <scope_posture>
            <included>
            - Continuous polling of funding rates across a configurable set of
              USDT-margined linear perpetual venues.
            - Normalized, append-only historical corpus suitable for offline
              research and calibration.
            - Anomaly detection and lifecycle tracking (birth → persistence →
              decay), with definition deferred (see `open_questions`).
            </included>
            <excluded>
            - Order execution, position management, PnL accounting — these
              belong to the separate Execution Engine.
            - Spot markets, options, coin-margined/inverse perps, quanto
              instruments.
            - Real-time alerting, dashboards, or UI layers in v1.
            </excluded>
        </scope_posture>

        <collection_layer type="Cron-Invoked Async Poller">
        A single `ccxt.async_support` script hitting bulk funding endpoints per
        exchange (per-symbol fallback where unavailable). Invoked by cron at
        fixed 60-second cadence (`* * * * *`); sub-minute resolution is
        explicitly out of scope until a concrete calibration need demonstrates
        otherwise.

        Three critical normalizations enforced at ingestion:

        - **Interval-agnostic APY**: $APY = r_{epoch} \times \frac{365 \times 24}{H_{epoch}}$,
          collapsing 1h/4h/8h venue heterogeneity into a comparable unit.
        - **Symbol canonicalization**: unified keys across venue-specific
          formats (e.g., `XRP/USDT:USDT` vs `XRPUSDT` vs `XRP-USDT-SWAP`).
        - **Quanto-risk rejection**: strictly filters for USDT-margined linear
          perps at ingestion; coin-margined, inverse, and quanto contracts are
          dropped before they touch the corpus.

        Poll cycles write directly to the current date partition. Cron's
        built-in supervision (restart-on-boot, per-invocation isolation, log
        capture via MTA or file redirection) is leveraged deliberately to avoid
        introducing a long-running daemon and its attendant ops surface.
        </collection_layer>

        <exchange_universe posture="dynamic">
        The set of monitored venues is **configuration-driven, not hardcoded**.
        A config file (YAML/TOML) enumerates active exchanges; adding or
        removing a venue is a config edit, not a code change. This keeps the
        collector agnostic to the eventual universe size and avoids baking in
        assumptions about "the 20 exchanges" or any other fixed count.

        Each entry carries: exchange id (ccxt convention), enabled flag,
        optional per-venue rate-limit overrides, optional symbol allowlist/
        blocklist. The loader validates that each configured venue exposes the
        funding endpoints the collector relies on at startup.
        </exchange_universe>

        <storage_layer>
            <format>Parquet, date-partitioned (`YYYY-MM-DD/`), append-only.</format>
            <schema name="funding_observation">
            - `ts_poll`            — UTC timestamp of the poll cycle (int64, ms)
            - `exchange`           — canonical exchange id (string)
            - `symbol_canonical`   — unified cross-venue symbol (string)
            - `symbol_native`      — raw venue symbol, preserved for audit (string)
            - `funding_rate`       — raw per-epoch rate $r_{epoch}$ (float64)
            - `funding_interval_h` — epoch length $H_{epoch}$ in hours (float32)
            - `apy_normalized`     — interval-agnostic APY (float64)
            - `mark_price`         — venue mark price at poll (float64, nullable)
            - `index_price`        — venue index price at poll (float64, nullable)
            - `next_funding_time`  — UTC timestamp of next epoch boundary
                                     (int64, ms) — required for epoch-boundary
                                     detection and "epochs survived" counting
            </schema>
        </storage_layer>

        <anomaly_layer status="deferred">
        Detection logic and the formal anomaly definition are explicitly
        out-of-scope for v1 of the collector. The corpus must be rich enough
        (raw per-poll observations, both rates and prices, with epoch-boundary
        markers) that any reasonable definition — z-score over rolling window,
        cross-venue spread threshold, APY percentile, or a learned detector —
        can be applied retroactively to the stored data. Definition to be
        settled once enough corpus exists to inspect the empirical
        distribution.
        </anomaly_layer>

        <hosting_model>
        **Local execution only.** The scanner runs on a single developer
        machine under the user's own cron. No VPS, no container orchestration,
        no remote service manager. This bounds the ops surface to:

        - a Python environment,
        - a crontab entry,
        - a local directory for the Parquet corpus.

        If corpus volume or uptime requirements ever outgrow a local host, the
        collection layer is designed to port to a VPS without code change
        (config-driven venues, cron-invoked, filesystem-only persistence), but
        that migration is not a v1 concern.
        </hosting_model>

        <non_goals>
        - No long-running daemon / service-manager integration.
        - No fixed exchange count or hardcoded venue list.
        - No anomaly-detection logic committed in v1.
        - No execution, no PnL, no alerting.
        - No sub-60s polling cadence.
        </non_goals>

        <open_questions status="tracked_not_blocking">
        - **Anomaly definition**: deferred until corpus inspection is possible.
        - **Exchange universe size**: intentionally variable; no target count.
        - **Corpus retention policy**: not yet specified (append-only for now;
          compaction/rollup strategy to revisit when partition sizes warrant).
        </open_questions>

    </project>

</context>